# **SIDDHARTH GARG**

i@siddharthgarg.in



9636249424

mww.siddharthgarg.in

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate developer, inquisitive, fast learner with experience in Full Stack Web Development and a specialist in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science. Well equipped with advanced level python, C++. Experience in creating end to end pipelines for data science projects. Deployed models on REST API, Object Detection on Raspberry Pi. IBM's Professional Certification in AI, Specialization in Deep Learning.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Computer Vision Engineer, FindMind **Analytics**

Feb 2020 - Present

Programmed a high accuracy end to end pipeline with a REST API for OCR and masking of client customer's sensitive documents using object detection, increasing speed 30x and accuracy to 97% from 60%

# **Deep Learning Lead, The Symbionic** Company

May 2020 - Present

Produced a Dataset and Developed a deep learning based object detection model for recognizing different grip patterns, to be fed into a 3D prosthetic robotic hand.

#### **POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY**

## Creative Head, **Mozilla Firefox Club VIT**

2019 - Present

Oversaw the club's activities, mentored designers, guided junior members in technical projects.

# Senior Core Committee Member, Technical Computer Society of India, VIT

2018 - 2019

Organized hackathons, lead workshops and programmed CTFs, with amazingly talented people I was fortunate enough to work with them on projects exposing students to new concepts.

# Marketing Head, Vellore Executive Board & Volunteer **ERIDE (NGO)**

2018 - Present

Empowering Rural India with Digital Education (ERIDE) aims on delivering digital literacy to underprivileged people. Joined as a freshman, from teaching kids in orphanages, community centres to leading the NGO as a board member.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winner, RCPC 2019

Competition, involving several Coding rounds by ACM, VIT

Runner Up, Hackathon by VIT

Hello World 2.0 hack conducted by VinnovateVIT

Winner, Jumble Ladder 2018

Competive Coding 2018, at Gravitas Technical Fest of VIT

DBMS Hackathon, VIT 2019, 3rd

Database Management Systems hackathon conducted by VIT

#### LINKS



# **EDUCATION**

# **Btech, Computer Science with Spec. in Bioinformatics**

VIT Vellore (Institute of Eminence)

2018 - Present **Current CGPA 8.9** 

#### 12th Grade, All India Senior School Certificate Examination (AISSCE)

Delhi Public School, RK Puram

2015 - 2017 Score: 90%

Subjects - Computer Science, Multimedia and Web-tech, English, Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry

#### 10th Grade, All India Secondary School Certificate (AISSC)

Delhi Public School, Agra

2007 - 2015 CGPA 9.4

#### SKILLS

#### **Programming**

Python, C++, C, Java, JavaScript, SQL

#### Machine Learning/ Al

CNNs, RNNs, Image Recognition, Sentiment Analysis, Topic Modeling, ObjectDetection, Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, Darknet

#### Web Development

Django, Flask, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, PHP, ReactJS

UI/UX

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Canva, Adobe XD

#### **PROJECTS**

## **REST API for OCR and masking of sensitive data in Identity documents** using image processing and object detection

Feb 2020 - Present

Sentiment Analysis and Topic Modelling of primetime News-hour Debates from different news channels

March 2020

# **Customer Segmentation using RFM technique**

December 2019

#### TB Saathi (Tuberculosis Diagnosis using neural networks tool) Nov 2019 2nd Prize in Hello World Hack by Vinnovate VIT

Minesweeper construction & solving algorithm Dec 2018 - April 2019

Extracting value of noised video dashboard of an aeroplane using

Sep 2018

#### **COURSEWORK**

video processing

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Discrete Mathematics | Database Management Systems | Operating Systems | Statistics for Engineers | Theory Of Computation and Compiler Design | Object Oriented Programming | Data Structures and Algorithms | Computer Architecture and Organization

#### ONLINE

**AI Engineering Professional Certificate by IBM** 

Machine Learning with Python | Deep Learning & Neural Networks with Keras | Scalable ML on Big Data using Apache Spark | Deep Neural Networks with PyTorch | Building Deep Learning Models with TensorFlow | Al Capstone Project with Deep Learning

Deep Learning Specialization by deeplearning.ai Sequence Models | Neural Networks & Deep Learning | Structuring Machine Learning Projects | Convolutional Neural Networks